

Hamza Tarique

Mern Stack Developer

About Me

I am an aspirant Mern Stack Developer and passionate about frontend, and backend technologies. I am responsible for writing reusable, testable, and efficient code and developing and designing front end web applications with two years of experience

My Contact

hamzatarique2000@gmail.com

+<u>923179654961</u>

Karachi,Sindh

<u>portfolio</u>

Hard Skill

- MUI
- Tailwind CSS
- Chakra UI
- Git/Github
- Redux/Toolkit
- Context API
- **ExpressJS**
- NodeJS
- ReactJS
- MongoDB

Soft Skill Languages

- Self-Motivated
- Decision making
- challenging
- English
- Urdu
- Panjabi
- Multi-tasking

Education Background

- University Of Sindh **Bachelors In Information Technology** 2019-2022
- Govt Boys High School (KGM) Intermediate in Pre Engineering Completed in 2018
- Govt Boys High School (KGM) Matriculation in Science Completed in 2015

Work Experience

Mern Stack Developer

Feb 2023 – Present (Ghani Business Solution) Key responsibilities:

- Responsible for coding APIs in nodejs/expressjs
- Responsible for integrating APIs in frontend usaully in ReactJS
- Responsible for handling state management in ReactJS with (Redux, Redux toolkit and context API).
- As a senior I provide guidance and support to internies throughout the training program

Mern Stack Developer

Oct 2022- Feb 2023 (Kxsoft)

Key responsibilities:

- Responsible for coding APIs in nodejs/expressjs
- Responsible for integrating APIs in frontend usaully in ReactJS

Mern Stack Developer

Jan 2021- Feb 2023 (Bachelors)

Key responsibilities:

- In this whole period I created many mern projects you may check my Github account and portfolio
- In FYP I created mern project (University Stock System) by own....
 - where I added many features like
- invoice genration
- email sending using nodemailer
- filteration with many features
- Stock maintenance and many more

Certificates

APR 2023	MongoDB Aggregation	ld :- MDBqkjilzuuus
APR 2023	MongoDB CRUD Operations in Node.js	Id :- MDBiphsutm4lm
APR 2023	MongoDB Node.js	Id:- MDBtw0vw771w5
APR 2023	MongoDB Transactions	Id:- MDBdt0b4r3f41